# Alzobair Elkhalifa

# **Software Engineer**

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Email: Alziber50@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://laitooo.vercel.app
Github: https://github.com/laitooo

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alziber50

## **Profile Summary**

Motivated Software developer with proven experience in mobile app development with some experience leading a team of 4 junior developers. I have 3 years of experience as a mobile app developer, 2 of them using flutter and 1 using Native Java/Kotlin. Successfully led, mentored junior developers into the best development practices, while doing code review ensuing high code quality. With some experience managing a team, assigning tasks, hiring and conducting interviews. In addition to 1 year of full-stack development experience my passion for learning led me to explore different fields, such as Game development, Artificial intelligence and Information technology.

## Work experience

#### Full Stack Software Developer | 249Startups | Egypt

2023/03 - Present

- Pioneered the creation of the Gaith funding program, which funded startups with over 2,000,000 euros, by Building and managing the Venture X platform using NextJs for the front-end and NestJs for the back-end (TypeScript).
- Led the automation of staff tasks which improved the staff task completion speed by 70%, achieved by Effective communication with different departments, gathering their incorporating them as a capability in the platform.

#### Flutter Team Leader | Fekra | Qatar

2022/09 - 2023/01

- Led and guided a team of 4 junior flutter developers, which built `Foodo`, a socially impactful application designed to combat food waste, for which I conducted task assignments, mentorship, and educating on the source code architecture.
- Managed the project effectively, which led to high code quality by doing thorough code reviews and adhering to best practices.
- Engaged in close collaboration with company stakeholders, fostering a cohesive and strategic approach to project management Articulating project requirements, establishing deadlines, and aligning development goals with overarching business objectives.
- Oversaw team management, which Ensured a high-quality team by doing screening and interviews and leading the hiring process.

## Senior Flutter developer | Fekra | Qatar

2021/12 - 2022/08

- Orchestrated communication with UI/UX team, ensuring seamless integration and user-centric design using effective communication.
- Took ownership of the client app, employing Firebase for database management and authentication and Google map, and Implementing CI/CD.
- Handled Firebase security ensuring app integrity and user trust, through applying Firebase security rules and unit testing.

#### Flutter developer | DoctorBase | Canada

2020/12 - 2021/11

- Played a pivotal role in refining DoctorBase, a telehealth app, which significantly improved patient experience and app ratings, by enhancing UI/UX design and streamlining virtual patient-doctor interactions.
- Participated in biweekly meetings that led to enhancement in the app user experience, by engaging in feature suggestions
- Optimized chat functionality for better user interaction, introducing efficient file management and visual communication features, thereby enhancing the overall functionality and user engagement.

#### **Education**

• University of Khartoum, B.Sc. in Civil Engineering, Khartoum, Sudan 2022

#### **Projects**

- Manga Online: Developed a highly successful flutter app for reading comics, with over 500000 downloads on Google Play and a 98% crash-free user rate, by continuous improvement and optimization.
- Bibliotheque: A flutter app for browsing, buying, and delivering books for clients.
- Forward: A flutter web app to a productivity juggernaut and weekly planner in one place.
- Werewolf Online: A multiplayer game with group voice chat built on an Android app front-end and a NodeJs server backend using webRTC.
- Plants vs Zombies 3D Clone: A replication of the popular game developed using Unity.
- Prediction of Compressive Strength using ANN: A machine learning project predicting concrete strength.

## **Skills**

- Flutter development: Flutter, Dart, Bloc, Hive, Firebase API, Git, CI/CD, Google Play Console.
- Android development: Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Dagger, Retrofit, Coroutines, WebRTC, Socket.io.
- Full stack development: NestJs, Node.js, NextJs (ReactJs), Kafka, Micro-services, HTML, CSS, tailwind, TypeScript, JavaScript, DaisyUI, Digital Ocean, Docker.
- Other skills: Game development using Unity (C#), Artificial Intelligence, and deep learning using Keras (Tensorflow) using Python.
- **Technical concepts:** Agile, Unit testing, Relational databases, Non-relational databases, UI/UX, Problem-solving, Debugging, Algorithms and data structures, Dependency injection, Software Architecture, Small understanding of A/B testing, and Test driven development (TDD).
- Soft skills: Collaboration, Mentorship, Effective communication, Problem-solving, Critical thinking, and Leadership.

- Arabic (Native) - English (Expert) - French (Beginner)